# **Liam Waters**

Gameplay programmer who loves turning ideas into fun, responsive experiences. Comfortable building mechanics, AI, and UI in C++ and Unity/Unreal always up for solving tricky problems with a creative twist. Passionate about making games that feel great to play, additionally love teaching and helping others when it comes to anything tech.

## Contact: liamwaters15@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Flix Interactive, Bromsgrove — Level 1 Gameplay Engineer JUN 2023 - PRESENT

Tasked with developing features and supporting releases as a support studio engineer, my responsibilities vary on a per client basis. I have worked professionally in both unreal engine and unity. Below I've listed the core responsibilities I've tackled.

- Console/Platform Development, Tooling and UI Programming
- Technical Designs and Implementations Feature work
- Optimisations, Profiling and bug fixes.
- Task scoping, delegation and Mentoring Juniors

#### We Game Games, Stoke-on-Trent — Technical Lead

#### FEB 2023 - APR 2023

A vertical slice startup where my responsibilities included game direction alongside the other discipline leads, end-to-end task management for juniors, establishing production pipelines between departments and supporting the overall welfare of the 21 person team.

### **Bulldog Studio,** Stoke-on-Trent — *Game Developer*

**JUN 2022 - AUG 2022** 

My responsibility was to design and implement features and organise cross-disciplinary meetings. Developed a 'metaverse' inspired project, led through Staffordshire University where the project achieved a gold Tiga award.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Staffordshire University,** Stoke-on-trent (92%) BSc(Hons) Games Design and Programming (First Class Honors)

**SEP 2020 - JUNE 2023** 

#### Lowestoft Sixth Form, Lowestoft

#### **SEP 2018 - JUNE 2020**

- BTEC level 3 ICT Extended Diploma (D\*, D\*, D\*) ~ Vocational 1,0
- BTEC level 3 Games Design: Merit ~ Vocational 2,7
- A-Level Mathematics: B ~ Abitur 2,0

#### **SKILLS**

Unreal Engine, Unity

C++, C#, JavaScript, Python, SQL, LINQ, .NET

**Games Networking** 

Task Management software (ADO, JIRA etc.)

Code Testing and Review frameworks ( Jenkins, Horde, etc. )

Physics and Maths for Games

AI Programming (HFSM, GOAP, BT)

UI Design and Implentation ( UMG, UIToolkit and uGui )

Procedural Animation

Proficient in the office suite (WORD, PPT, EXCEL)

3D Modelling and 3D Animation

#### **AWARDS**

National Citizen Service

Duke Of Edinburgh Bronze.

#### **LANGUAGES**

**English Native**